

# Pengyan Lu Male · Bachelor · 17 years 5 month experience

Mobile: 13520788176

Email: lupengyan@hotmail.com

### Self-description

17 years experience in software development, I have worked on the development of e-commerce websites, social networking sites, content management systems, various Windows desktop applications, mobile applications, and machine learning technology, makes me have deep knowledge and understanding in software design, architecture, development, and testing. I'm competent for technical managers, architects, technical officers and senior software engineer. The philosophy of being serious and responsible for the work and the ultimate product concept is one's own policy of doing things that have never changed.

## Summary

#### Current

Income: 560.0 k(40000Yuan/Month\*14Months)
Industry: Internet/Mobile Internet/E-Business

Location: Beijing

Position: Technical Manager

Job Seeking Status: On job, open for new job

## Experience

#### Beijing Mijinghefeng Technology Co., Ltd.

2016.06-Now

Technical Manager

Responsibilities & Achievements:

Technical Manager/Senior iOS Engineer/Machine Learning Engineer

- 1. Lead the development of new mobile projects
- 2. iOS app architecture and function design
- 3. Apply Flutter technology on Huajiao live app and some new projects
- 4. Research and implement audio and video technology
- 5. Research and implement the audio and video deep learning technology

2014.12-2016.05

#### Beijing Qihoo 360 Technology Co., Ltd.

Senior iOS engineer

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- 1. Lead and develop the iOS 360 VOIP app and make it a timely launch.
- 2. Lead some iOS engineers to overcome all difficulties, and iterate quickly to make the Huajiao Live Stream app published early and grab the Live stream market at that time.

2014.06-2014.12

#### Beijing Mentor Education Technology Co., Ltd.

iOS Technical Manager

Responsibilities & Achievements:

Lead and develop the Mentor app in one month

2012.06-2014.06

#### Beijing Kingsoft Software Co., Ltd.

iOS Technical Manager

Responsibilities & Achievements:

Responsible for the development, maintenance and upgrade of related iOS products under the Kingsoft PowerWord brand, as well as the management of the entire team.

Through rapid iteration and optimized performance, Kingsoft PowerWord has reached 5 stars in each successive version in the App Store, and the crash rate is controlled at one in ten thousand.

2004.05-2012.06

#### Beijing Shinetech Software Inc.

Business manager

Responsibilities & Achievements:

After 8 years of work here, I started as a junior programmer, and through my unremitting efforts, I became the head of the business department and the chief iOS engineer. The main responsibility is to be responsible for the daily affairs of the business department, project management and the chief iOS programmer. The pursuit of details and diligence are the cornerstones of my work. In addition, most of the projects are the European and American customers so my English communication of reading, writing and speaking improved qualitatively.

In more than three years, nearly 50 iOS applications have been designed and developed, and they have all been submitted to the App Store. These applications involve games, entertainment, books, tools, commerce, medical care, and so on.

#### Education

Beihang University Computer science and 2001.09-2004.07

Technology/Bachelor

Beijing Institute of Machinery Computer application/College 1998.09-2001.06

Industry

### **Project Experience**

Huajiao Live Stream 2015.11-Now

iOS Senior Engineer

Beijing Mijinghefeng Technology Co., Ltd

Description:

The mobile live broadcast platform, mainly show and performance live broadcast, users can interact with the host, including chat, video calling, gifting, games, etc.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Software architecture design, participated in the development of most modules such as live stream, watch player, K song, private message, video clip, and gift system.
- 2. Technical research, such as karaoke sound effects, real-time sound monitoring, beauty system, AI technology, etc.
- 3. Lead to improve the ability of members
- 4. Lead the team to iterate quickly and sometimes one version per week

Accomplishments:

From the tens of thousands of daily activities at the end of 2015 to the current daily activities of tens of millions. This ensures that the Huajiao live app has sprung up in the live app battle.

### Jiaoyan Live Show(椒盐直综)

2019.03-2019.10

iOS Technical Manager

Beijing Mijinghefeng Technology Co., Ltd

Description:

Live variety show platform, there are several categories, you can also participate in the show by sending messages, and support playback.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Participate in Flutter development
- 2. Design Flutter and native interactive architecture
- 3. Flutter problem solving

Accomplishments:

- 1. Hybrid development of Flutter and native
- 2. Improved project progress through Flutter development.

Maobo live(猫啵直播) 2018.03-2018.11

Mobile Technical Manager

Beijing Mijinghefeng Technology Co., Ltd

Description:

Huajiao produced a pan-entertainment social live-stream product specifically for the PC side. The hosts can only go live on a PC, and the audience watches the live stream on a mobile device.

Responsibilities:

Responsible for mobile iOS and Android development tasks, and participate in the development of iOS architecture and development.

Accomplishments:

Ensure the smooth launch of the two platforms in a short time

**360 free VOIP** 2014.12-2015.12

iOS senior engineer

Beijing Qihoo 360 Technology Co., Ltd.

Description:

360 free VOIP is a free phone call software. It has a powerful secure cloud contact synchronization function.

You don't have to worry about losing your contacts. You can make free calls using a cell network even if the other party does not install the app.

Responsibilities:

Responsible for the architecture design, the development of the address book module, and the free phone module.

Kingsoft PowerWord 2012.06-2014.06

iOS Technical Manager

Beijing Kingsoft Software Co., Ltd.

Description:

Responsible for managing the iOS team and finishing the following apps:

- 1. Kingsoft
- 2. Kingsoft PowerWord HD
- 3. Kingsoft Memorize Words
- 4. UFO Kid
- 5. VOA Slow English

Responsibilities:

- 1. Project management: ensure the smooth completion of each iteration in terms of time, and technically guide development engineers to work on coding and unit testing.
- 2. Research, design and implement the iOS architecture.
- 3. Discuss the business requirements with the product manager.
- 4. Make code conventions, write technical documents, improve code quality
- 5. Provide technical training to the members of the group.

Accomplishments:

- 1. Make sure the project is updated quickly and iteratively
- 2. Optimize and improve word search performance

iOS Development

Business manager

Beijing Shinetech Software Inc.

Description:

We developed nearly 50 iOS applications In more than three years, and all of them have been submitted to the App Store. These applications involve categories of games, entertainment, books, tools, commerce, medical care, and so on.

Responsibilities:

As a division manager and senior iOS programmer, I'm responsible for requirements analysis, project evaluation & quotation, delivery schedule, architecture design and quality control.

Accomplishments:

Developed apps include:

BusinessCard Box

Do as the locals do

The Magic Key

Send2Mobiles

Fun-Swings Golf Scorer

Shark Attack Revenge

**Toddler Tweets** 

Robinson ADHD College Tracker

Success by John Echberg

**Pocket Souls** 

Military Wife

iAsthma in Control

iAutism Toddler Screening Tool

iToddler Tamer

Calories

iPad apps include

Movie Club

Rise of the Urban Eagle

Train Trouble

Braas

.NET development 2004.07-2008.12

Senior Software Engineer

Beijing Shinetech Software Inc.

Description:

- 1. Websites built based on ASP.NET and ASP.NET MVC involve e-commerce, social networking, CMS, etc.
- 2. The Windows desktop application Real Options Super Lattice Solver implemented in C# is used for real options analysis.
- 3. A Com add-in for Microsoft Office Excel named Risk Simulator is used for risk simulation analysis and data

analysis.

Responsibilities:

Responsible for requirements analysis and software development.

Accomplishments:

- 1. Website goes online smoothly.
- 2. Ensure the smooth delivery of desktop applications to global customers.

# Languages

English, Mandarin